Inventory of the Ernest Wilson Riggs papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ernest Wilson Riggs papers
1919-1943
XX295
Riggs, Ernest Wilson, 1881-1952.
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.2 linear feet)
Memoirs and correspondence, relating to Turkish atrocities against Armenians in 1915; the expulsion of Americans from Turkey, 1920-1921; Turkish-American relations; and conditions in Greece during World War II.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
President, Euphrates College, Harput, Turkey, 1910-1921; Child Welfare Director, Near East Relief, 1920-1921.
Scope and Content of Collection
Memoirs and correspondence, relating to Turkish atrocities against Armenians in 1915; the expulsion of Americans from Turkey, 1920-1921; Turkish-American relations; and conditions in Greece during World War II.
Near East Relief (Organization); Armenian massacres, 1915-1923.; International relief.; Turkey--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Turkey.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Turkey.; World War, 1939-1945--Greece.
- "Murder of Rev. G. P. Knapp, Head of the American Mission, Bitlis,", 1919 October 16 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Letter, W. Nesbitt Chambers to Dr. Peet, 1921 November 5 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Press release, U.S. Dept. of State, "Negotiation of a Treaty of Amity and Commerce between the United States and Turkey,", 1923 August 6 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- "Some Events at Harpoot during the Great War of 1914-1915,", undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Correspondence of Ernest W. Riggs, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 5-6)
- Letter, A. W. Dulles, U. S. Dept. of State, to Rev. E. Starks Beebe, mimeograph copy, 1924 March 5 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Letter, Theodore D. Riggs to friends, 1921 April 17 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Irwin, Genevieve DuVal (Mrs. H. M.). "War Notes, with an Addenda--On Saving of Enclosed 'War Notes'." (two copies), undated (Box-folder 1: 9-10)
- Jaquith, H. C.. Letter to Admiral Mark L. Bristol, concerning events in Smyrna, September 9-16, 1922, 1922 October 11 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Ward, Mark. Extracts from the diary of Mark Ward, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 1: 12)